<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>13 Feats + Feats fixes</name>
        <description>5e Homebrew</description>
        <author url="http://www.wargamevault.com/product/174073/13-Feats--Feat-Fixes-5e">Supreme Slayer</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="13-feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Waphles/DnD/Homebrew/master/Feats/13-feats.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Bully" type="Feat" source="5e Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_FEAT_BULLY">
        <supports />
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p><i></i></p>
            <p>You've mastered the brutal art of kicking your opponent while they're down and taking advantage of any and every opening you can find, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have Advantage on Opportunity Attacks.</li>
                <li>You are granted an Opportunity Attack when a creature within your reach attemps to stand up from being Prone.</li>
                <li>When you are granted an Opportunity Attack against a creature, instead of a melee attack you may choose to perform a Shove attempt against that creature, with Advantage on your roll.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.wargamevault.com/product/174073/13-Feats--Feat-Fixes-5e</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>You've mastered the brutal art of kicking your opponent while they're down and taking advantage of any and every opening you can find.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Second Skin" type="Feat" source="5e Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_FEAT_SECOND_SKIN">
        <supports />
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p><i></i></p>
            <p>You've become so accustomed to wearing your armor that it no longer feels like it's there to you, granting the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>You don and doff armor in half the normal time, or 1/4 the normal time if assisted.</li>
                <li>You can don or doff a shield using your free item interaction for the turn, instead of as an action.</li>
                <li>While moving at half your normal speed or resting, you do not take any penalties or disadvantages to your ability checks normally imposed by wearing medium or heavy armor.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.wargamevault.com/product/174073/13-Feats--Feat-Fixes-5e</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>You've mastered the brutal art of kicking your opponent while they're down and taking advantage of any and every opening you can find.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
          <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Second Skin" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Oversized Weapon Mastery" type="Feat" source="5e Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_FEAT_OVERSIZED_WEAPON_MASTERY">
        <supports />
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p><i></i></p>
            <p>You've hardened your grip and learned the way to heft and balance typically unwieldy weapons and equipment easily. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You may wield a two-handed melee weapon in one hand, or may use a versatile weapon in one hand and use its two handed weapon die for damage. You may only wield one such weapon this way at a time. If you are a race with the Small size, replace the ability to wield a two-handed melee weapon in one hand with the following benefit instead: You ignore the Heavy property of weapons.</li>
                <li>When you throw a weapon as an improvised thrown weapon attack, the damage dealt on a hit is equal to the weapon damage dice of the weapon.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.wargamevault.com/product/174073/13-Feats--Feat-Fixes-5e</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>You've hardened your grip and learned the way to heft and balance typically unwieldy weapons and equipment easily.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>
